ABU JAMES

Ibadan Oyo State

Mobile No: 08066297341

E-Mail: jamesabu4us@yahoo.com

PERSONAL ATTRIBUTE

An enthusiastic graduate of psychology who through diverse training has acquired a number of valuable

skills these include good interpersonal and communication skill, ability to analyse problems and to think

critically: the ability to interpret and evaluate research including statistics.

Team Work

Working as part of several project implementation teams and has continually made me demonstrate team

building skills that assure morale, encourage planning, organization, co-ordination and commitment

Database Skills

Analyzing health data stored predominantly in excel. I have an excellent background in data analysis and a

practical experience in monitoring and manipulating a database to provide a high availability service, superb

attention to detail with a great love of working with numbers

A well developed, proficient knowledge of all Microsoft Office: Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Access, very

good presentation skills as I gave regular presentations as at school and work. I am a quick learner and have

a very quick grasp; I find it easy understanding unfamiliar computer applications as I have very well honed

computer application and development skills.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

(2014-2016)

Worked with Family Health International as a Data Service Officer (SIDHAS project Akwa Ibom

State) with M&E unit

Job Responsibilities:

Contribute to the successful implementation of Outreach & community ART linkage & integration to the

facility (Hub) PMM system.

• Ensure daily, weekly & monthly summary data and source documents (patient/client forms, registers and

summary forms) are up to date and assist in updating service registers and preparation of summary reports

1

during reporting period and when necessary making sure that all outreach/community ART service statistics are well reflected in facility PME & Chronic Care tools.

- Support the accurate transcription of PMM & Care and Support documentation from the cART source documents into the facility(Hub) registers
- Works with Facility (Hub) service providers (or the M&E focal persons) to ensure that all outreach & community ART sites data is reported within the facility service statistics
- Work with both the M&E focal persons & outreach documentation support officer to resolve questions, inconsistencies or missing/incomplete data from any of the service delivery areas.
- Retrieves and sorts data source documents (both Hub & Community ART) clients for electronic database entries, identifies and interprets data to be entered into specific modules. Verifies accuracy of data, checks for outliers/variance and correct before entry into any electronic systems.
- Maintains confidentiality of information on source documents or in databases and assists in establishing and maintaining an effective and efficient records management system with good audit trail
- Confirms accuracy of data by comparing data entered with source documents. Also triangulates collected data across the cART SDPs. Reviews and makes necessary corrections to information captured as required
- Generates daily ,weekly & monthly summary reports and support any operational research on the outreach/community ART implementation
- Assist in management of client personal records including retrieval and filing of folders.
- Participate in Data Quality Assessments, Joint Data Quality Assessments and Data Validation exercises at the state level
- Assist in generating regular gap analysis to show regional/state/site progress towards achieving set targets
- Participate in periodic data quality assessments at FHI360 Akwa Ibom supported sites and generate reports
- Regular update of indicator reports tracker
- Contribute to the development of lessons learned from outreach/community ART to service documentation of HIV/AIDS, PMTCT, RH/FP, TB and integrated medical services and apply these lessons to improve the design of new and existing programs
- Liaises with the State coordinating Team to ensure effective Comm. ART tools inventory management system

(February-June 2016)

. Data Entry Clerk/Research Assistant

African Network for Care of Children Affected by HIV/AIDS (ANECCA), Nigeria Catalyzing Access to quality services for Children and Adolescents living with HIV." (CACA).GF Grant

As a Data Entry clerk I was primarily responsible for data preparation and entry of client data from the questionnaires into the ANECCA PROJECT database. Additional responsibilities as required are collection, collating and reporting of data, routine quality checks in terms of documentation.

- Collection of data by administering questionnaires (Key Informant Interview. Structured questionaries' & Client Exist Interview).
- Collation of data.
- Data management and analysis.
- Support the development of final report.

- Assist the field supervisor in the planning, implementation and review of data collection and other M&E activities for ANECCA project at the selected health facilities.
- Routinely check of incoming client completeness, internal coherence and accuracy and work with client for ensuring proper completion of the questionnaires.
- Prior to data entry, verify and edit data to ensure compatibility with data entry system and procedural requirements.
- Enter data into the ANECCA project database in an accurate, consistent and timely manner and according to prescribed format.
- Back up the data entered as and when necessary.
- When needed, work with other ANECCA staff and national consultants.

(2016 till Date)

School Counselor at Royal Favour Comprehensive College Akobo Ibadan

Job Responsibilities:

- Listen to students' concerns about academic, emotional or social problems
- Help students process their problems and plan goals and action
- Mediate conflict between students and teachers
- Improve parent/teacher relationships
- Assist with college applications, jobs and scholarships
- Facilitate drug and alcohol prevention programs
- Organize peer counseling programs
- Refer students to psychologists and other mental health resources
- Work on academic boards to improve learning conditions

National Youth Service Corps

NYSC at Army Day Secondary School Odogbo Ojoo Ibadan

(2012-2013)

Trainings Attended

MEASURE evaluation/ USAID online resource centre.

June 2015

M & E fundamentals, a self-guided online mini course

Epidemic Control Orientation Training (M&E fundamentals and Basics of HIV/AIDS) June 2015 Data collection/Analysis and Tools for Research Assistant/Data Entry clerk Feb 2016

Personal Attributes

Interpersonal skill
Strong analytical skill
Quick learning ability
Effective communication skill
Good team player
Ability to manage pressure

Other Skills Good knowledge of MS Office applications (Excel, Word and Power Point)		
EDUCATION/CERTIFICATES		
NATIONAL YOUTH SERVICE CORPS	(2012- 2013)	
Certificate of national service	(2022 2020)	
University of Ibadan, Ibadan Oyo State B.sc Psychology (Second Class Upper Division) MSC (In view) International Corporation and Humanitarian Aid. Kalu	(2007-2011) Institute Spain(2018-2019)	
Army Day Secondary School AdekunleFajuyi Cantonment Ibadan	(1996-2002)	
Senior Secondary School Certificate (SSCE)		
Army Children School AdekunleFajuyi Cantonment Ibadan First leaving Certificate	(1990-1996)	
INTEREST AND HOBBIES I enjoy, travelling and reading.		
REFERENCE		
Ekelechukwu Nwabuisi		
Technical Officer (M/E)		
Family Health International Uyo Akwa Ibom State 08034395335		
ekelecwabuisi100@gmail.com		
2. Dr.Mac Abel Abu Senior Technical Officer		

Family Health International (FHI360) Uyo Akwa Ibom State 08038258268 abumacabel@yahoo.com

3. Prof.Fagbola Lecturer Department of Agronomy University of Ibadan 08058483474